

847-528-2326

full resume at:

adamkosecki@gmail.com http://adamkosecki.com/

I am Adam Kosecki, a professional web developer with 10+ years of experience. I create things that are clean; from beautiful, straightforward, comprehensible design elements to robust & readable code.

I strive to understand a problem from all angles before outlining a solution. My solutions are a fair compromise between form and function, fanciness and efficiency, seriousness and fun.

I am a leader. I make decisions when appropriate, and defer or delegate without shame. People respect me and enjoy working for me.

LANGUAGES

My bread and butter.

JavaScript, PHP, SQL, CSS/LESS, HTML, ColdFusion

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, Programming Emphasis Minor in Psychology

Western Illinois University 2000-2004

EXPERIENCE

Clear Software

VP OF PRODUCT 2015 - Present Currently evangelizing best practices and modern development techniques for this startup; breathing new life in to old UIs; and leading the product's transition from an on-premise, single-user solution to a multi-tenant, SaaS, cloud application.

HelpSystems

SENIOR DEVELOPER

2014 - 2015 / Full-time 2015 - Present / Consultant Developed and deployed an HTML5, mobile-first invoicing application in PHP/AngularJS/MySql to facilitate an end-to-end process for online ordering and payments. The application included a robust API allowing it to integrate with multiple, disparate back-end systems.

Provided guidance regarding front end user experience, SEO, and deployment for the company's public web entities.

Implemented massive ETL processes to migrate and synchronize data between HelpSystems and Network Automation servers throughout the acquisition process.

Network Automation

LEAD UI DESIGNER

MS SQL DBA

2005 - 2014

Created entire public web entity for company, including all visual design elements, technological decisions (language/framework/server), coding, SEO decisions, optimization for user experience & retention, and... everything else:

Lead on-borading / Customer online account / Marketing content / Product downloads / Shopping cart system / License issuing / Support ticketing system / Customer Resource Center / Channel Partner Portal / CMS for marketing and support content.

Served as company DBA, implementing best practices including full normalization of existing MS SQL database.

Inherited, managed, enhanced, and enriched existing (homegrown) corporate CRM.